<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An instance of the repentance of a late passive-obedience-parson, who was lately a justice of peace in the county of Hereford</title>
            <author>Pugh, Hugh.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1690</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A56260</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P4184A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R7245</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99834127</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99834127</idno>
            <idno type="VID">38623</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A56260)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 38623)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1958:2)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An instance of the repentance of a late passive-obedience-parson, who was lately a justice of peace in the county of Hereford</title>
                  <author>Pugh, Hugh.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet (2 p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>printed in the year 1690]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed at end: H. Pughe.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Herefordshire (England) --  History --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-12</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="submission">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:38623:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>AN INSTANCE OF THE REPENTANCE OF A LATE
PASSIVE-OBEDIENCE-PARSON, Who was lately a Juſtice of Peace in the County of
<hi>Hereford.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>I <hi>Hugh Pugh</hi> of <hi>Dorſon</hi> in the County of
<hi>Hereford,</hi> Clerk, being ſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible of my baſe and uncharitable
Actings towards <hi>S— L—</hi> of <hi>Fanhope</hi> in the ſaid
County of <hi>Hereford,</hi> 
               <abbr>Esq</abbr> one of Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties
Juſtices of the Peace for the ſaid County; and being diſturbed in my Soul
for the Forgery I cauſed to be made of High-Treaſon againſt the ſaid
<hi>S— L—;</hi> and likewiſe for thoſe Actions of Defamation I
ſent to the Lord Commiſſioner <hi>Keck,</hi> and other Nobles; that is to
ſay, unto the Duke of <hi>Ormond,</hi> and the Earl of <hi>Monmouth:</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Do acknowledge, That I was guilty of, and adviſed and directed
to the Earl of <hi>Monmouth,</hi> in theſe words following, <hi>viz. Theſe
for the Right Honourable the Earl of</hi> Monmouth, <hi>to be communicated to
the King and Queens moſt Excellent Majeſties, with all poſſible
ſpeed, for the Diſcovery of High-Treaſon againſt Them.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="oath">
                        <p>
                           <hi>Hereford</hi> ff.
<q rend="margQuotes">'<hi>John Scudamore</hi> of
<hi>Ken-Church</hi> in the ſaid County, <abbr>Esq</abbr> one of Their
Majeſties Juſtices of the Peace for the ſaid County, and <hi>Thomas
Delahay</hi> of <hi>Hayury</hi> in the ſaid County, <abbr>Esq</abbr> one of
Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Juſtices of the Peace for the ſaid County, make Oath,
That <hi>S— L—,</hi> 
                              <abbr>Esq</abbr> one of Their Majeſties
Juſtices of the Peace for the ſaid County, did on <hi>Monday</hi> laſt,
being the twenty-ninth day of this inſtant <hi>July, Anno<expan>
                                    <am>
                                       <g ref="char:abque"/>
                                    </am>
                                    <ex>que</ex>
                                 </expan> Dom.</hi>
1689. in the evening, in their hearing, ſay, <hi>That he the ſaid</hi>
S— L—<hi> abhorred King</hi> William <hi>and Queen</hi> Mary
<hi>with a perfect hatred, and heartily wiſhed their utter Deſtruction, and
that he might be ſo happy as to be inſtrumental therein; and that he had
made a very great preparation in order thereunto, and did not doubt of perfect
ſucceſs in the ſame</hi>
                           </q>
                        </p>
                        <p>And theſe Deponents further make Oath, That they
really believe the Contents hereof to be very true, and that they vehemently
ſuſpect the Murther of their Perſons, and Burning of their Houſes, if
they be known
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:38623:2"/>
to detect the premiſed Deſigns, before the ſaid
<hi>S— L—</hi> be Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonally ſecured.</p>
                        <closer>Jurat
<date>triceſſimo die Julii Anno Regni Gulielmi &amp;
Mariae Regis &amp; Reginae, Angliae &amp;c. primo Anno<expan>
                                 <am>
                                    <g ref="char:abque"/>
                                 </am>
                                 <ex>que</ex>
                              </expan> Dom.
<hi>1689.</hi>
                           </date>
                           <signed>Coram me, <hi>Ja. Woodhouſe.</hi>
                           </signed>
                           <signed>
                              <list>
                                 <item>J. Scudamore,</item>
                                 <item>Tho. Delahay.</item>
                              </list> 
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="testimony">
                        <p>
                           <q rend="margQuotes">'All which was of my Malicious
Contrivance, and that I cauſed to be forged the Hands of <hi>John
Scudamore,</hi> 
                              <abbr>Esq</abbr> and <hi>Tho. Delahay,</hi> 
                              <abbr>Esq</abbr>
two of Their Majeſties Juſtices for the ſaid County; and likwiſe, the
Hand of <hi>James Woodhouſe,</hi> 
                              <abbr>Esq</abbr> before whom the ſaid
forged Affidavit is ſuppoſed to be taken. And I do heartily repent me of
the ſame, and humbly beg Pardon of Almighty God, and the ſaid <hi>S—
L—,</hi> for attempting to take away his Life, and good Fame, by ſuch
my Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lanous Forgery; and likewiſe, I humbly beg Pardon of the ſaid
<hi>John Scu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>damore, Th. Delahay,</hi> and <hi>Ja. Woodhouſe,</hi> for
preſuming to forge their Hands, to Countenance ſuch a diſhoneſt
Attempt. And I confeſs my ſelf guil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of Writing, Inditeing, and Sending
that Letter to the Lord Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner <hi>Keck</hi> in theſe Words,
<hi>viz.</hi>
                           </q> 
                           <hi>To the Right Honourable my Lord Commiſſioner</hi>
Keck, <hi>of the High Court of</hi> Chancery, <hi>at his Houſe in</hi>
Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cery-Lane, London.
<q rend="margQuotes">Honourable Sir, Mr.
<hi>S— L—,</hi> a Juſtice of Peace for <hi>Herefordſhire,</hi>
is a great Countenancer of Rogues, to buſy inſolent, and abuſive to
Perſons of Quality, a great Scandal to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion, and Diſhonour
to God, and Their Majeſties; much alienating the Hearts of true Proteſtants
and Loyal Subjects. And the Conſequence may prove dreadful, if he be not
ſpeedily Superceded; and that your Honour may ſo do, is the humble Petition
of your Honour's moſt hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Servant,</q>
                        </p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>H. Pughe.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="testimony">
                        <p>
                           <q rend="margQuotes">'All which ſaid Offences, I
humbly beg Pardon for, and do Confeſs and Acknowlege, that I had no Reaſon
or Pretence ſo to do; but on the contrary, I am very well aſſured, That
the ſaid <hi>S— L—</hi> never deſerved any ſuch Character
from me, or any other Perſon whatſoever; And that I had no Inducement, but
the Inſtigation of the Devil, to cauſe me to Defame the ſaid <hi>S—
L—;</hi> and I humbly make this Submiſſion and Recantation, and do
atteſt all the Contents hereof to be unfeigned and true; and out of the Sence
of my Errors humbly in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treat the ſaid <hi>S— L—</hi> to accept
hereof. In witneſs whereof, I put my hand and Seal hereunto, the
<hi>21ſt</hi> of <hi>January, Anno<expan>
                                    <am>
                                       <g ref="char:abque"/>
                                    </am>
                                    <ex>que</ex>
                                 </expan> Dom.</hi> 1689/90.</q>
                        </p>
                        <closer>
                           <dateline>Signed, Sealed, Confeſſed, and Subſcribed</dateline>
                           <signed>in the preſence of
<list>
                                 <item>J. Scudamore,</item>
                                 <item>Robert Minors,</item>
                                 <item>John Hereford,</item>
                                 <item>Tho. Morgan.</item>
                                 <item>H. Pughe.</item>
                              </list>
                           </signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>I do atteſt this to be a true Copy of Mr. <hi>Pughe</hi>'s
Submiſſion, and ſhall be ready to prove the ſame when required.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Witneſs my Hand, <date>this 13th day of <hi>February,</hi> 1689/90.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>S— L—.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed in the Year 1690.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
